LAUGHING MAN FANSUBS
I'm a soldier - that means I'm
Both a defendant and the judge
I am standing on both ends of the flame
Rounding curves
Overtaking life and death,
I run and fight with false shadows
No matter how many threads of
deception are woven together,
The truth shall illuminate
the face of light
Save your tears for the day
When our pain is far behind
On your feet, come with me
We are soldiers stand or die
Save your fears, take your place
Save them for the judgement day
Fast and free, follow me
Time to make the sacrifice.
We rise or fall
Niihama Residential Refugee Sector
Sealed District
All teams, designate target building.
Operation code is I-S.
Repeat, operation code is I-S.
NEMESIS
HQ to all teams. The armed refugees possess
a sentient tank; exercise extreme caution.
Repeat, the armed refugees are armed with
J-1, execute Code I-S and support mobile troops.
Neutralise the target upon discovery.
Repeat, neutralise the target upon discovery.
Affirmative.
Even if this is just a drill,
I've got to blow up the real thing at least once.
J-1, your pulse rate is above normal.
Do you have a medical anomaly?
I'm fine. I'm good... to go.
All teams, we have reached the target.
Unit R-D has completed drop.
Unit S-D has completed drop.
Unit W-R has completed drop.
Unit S-J has begun wire drop.
Unit S-W has begun wire drop.
Go, go, go, go!
Unit G-2 has neutralised target.
Unit G-3 has neutralised target; unable
to confirm presence of sentient tanks.
Unit G-4 is also clear; we have
neutralised the armed refugees.
We are unable to confirm the
presence of sentient tanks.
Target confirmed!
The target has weapons-lock on your unit.
Bastard!
J-1, your pulse rate is above normal again.
Are you still operational?
Shut up!
Even if we're only using dummy shots,
who the hell could stay calm
with that alarm blaring?!
Gotch...
J-1, report!
Your pulse rate is zero.
We have an emergency.
It appears that J-1's pilot has died
in the cockpit; cause undetermined.
The support AI has engaged the autopilot.
At present, J-1's flight status is
stable and there is no danger of a crash.
HA-01AV, disengage Code I-S
and return to ship ASAP.
Repeat, disengage Code I-S
Attention all teams: we have an emergency.
This is not a drill.
J-1's pilot died in his
cockpit for undetermined reasons.
Disengage Code I-S to prevent
any further chance of fatalities.
Execute Code S-A and retreat.
Repeat, execute Code S-A and retreat.
HA-01AV has not disengaged Code I-S.
Its pilot's life signs still read all green.
While his cardiac arrest has been confirmed,
there are still vital signals from his cyberbrain.
We believe this led the support AI to ignore retreat signals
from the control tower and to prioritise the pilot's safety.
The AI appears to have decided that
the retreat code was an enemy attack...
H-Hey, the Wasps...
Department of Defence
Kubota.
Aramaki.
It seems the situation requires expediency.
It seems you just can't help digging into anything when there's
even the slightest possibility that a crime's involved.
For now, we've told the media that the operation was
an aerial refuelling drill for units in development.
In reality, it was the largest scale classified
live-fire drill in the past three years.
It was conducted in light of the government's
upcoming implementation of the new refugee policy.
Wasn't the machine in question
the same sentient helicopter
that got a lot of attention for alleged collusion
with the American Empire regarding our security alliance?
Actually, that's not it.
The GSDF feared the media's attack,
GSDF = Ground Self Defence Force
so they apparently participated in the drill using one
of their own models modified to integrate AI-Support,
and dubbed it the Digger Wasp Advance.
The GSDF believes that this incident
occurred because the pilot died accidentally.
Given all that information, don't you think
the current situation is too suspicious?
I can't slip anything by you, can I?
So, how far towards the truth
has your team penetrated?
During the live-fire drill,
the pilot of an AI-assisted anti-tank helicopter
collapsed at approximately 5:57 AM,
after which the support AI's autopilot takeover seemingly
resolved the situation, without further problems.
However, the AI proceeded to ignore the code
disengagement command from the control tower,
and entered the residential
refugee sector's airspace at 6:03.
Furthermore, the AI simultaneously
hacked two of its sister units
and an airborne refuelling unit that
were stationed on the aircraft carrier.
Furthermore, the AI simultaneously
hacked two of its sister units
and an airborne refuelling unit that
were stationed on the aircraft carrier.
These three hacked units took off
from the aircraft carrier at 6:12.
They rendezvoused in the
residential refugee sector
and are apparently still
circling above the radio tower.
That's about right.
In addition, there is an unconfirmed
report that two sister units
from the military garrison in Awaji
and three from the garrison in Wakayama
have also taken off unmanned, under online guidance.
That is also correct.
Bases that received word of the incident immediately
engaged autistic mode on all other sister units.
but two more units took off from
Itami, which was slow to respond.
What of the possibility that this is an act of
cyber-terrorism that's targeting the support AIs?
Getting past a military firewall
to do that would be very difficult.
Taking the possibility of
terrorism into consideration,
our intelligence division has already detained all personnel
who were involved in the support AI's development
and is currently conducting an investigation,
but nothing has been found.
What about the possibility of an armed
uprising by hotheads within the ranks?
That's not possible, either.
The particularists couldn't have influenced them.
We even suspected team members who were
part of the hedonist cult, Stabat Mater,
which has been singled out
by the media for attack.
That wasn't the case either?
The leadership is desperate to bring the situation
under control by passing it off as an accident.
Fortunately, the attack choppers are
only circling above the radio tower.
One hopes that's all that'll come of it.
The refugees, eh...?
And that's what he has to say, Major.
His information is neither more
nor less than what we've obtained.
But it looks like the district has been brought under
the control of the Prefectural Police's mobile troops.
Not only the angry refugees.
But the GSDF mobile troops, who came to bring the
situation under control, appear to be denied entry.
The Prefectural Police claim
that they were the ones
who were putting their lives on the
line trying to exercise jurisdiction.
Pathetic.
It's terminal.
Just in case, I'm having Togusa and Ishikawa
investigate the supposedly-deceased pilot's home;
So what do you want us to do?
We've almost reached the
residential refugee sector.
For now, get close to the target and stand by.
I'll wait for the Prime Minister's final decision as to
whether this situation falls within our jurisdiction.
Roger.
What I said does not leave this room.
It'd be trouble enough if someone
were to see me with you like this.
What...
You still can't abandon ambition?
I'm sorry, but I can't live life the way you do.
Excuse me.
You must be Mr. Aramaki from
Public Safety's Section 9.
Cabinet Intelligence Agency, Investigative
Council for Possible Changes to Wartime Strategy,
That would be Gouda Kazundo.
Gouda Kazundo
Representative Aide
It's not often that I come across
people who can read my name correctly,
even though I don't believe it's all that unusual.
But now, I believe it is a very good name.
After all, once I tell people the correct
way to say it, most people will remember.
Especially when they associate it with this face.
So, what business does the Cabinet
Intelligence Agency have with me?
We would like Section 9's cooperation
to handle the present situation;
we knew that it would be impolite to ask,
but I decided to approach you directly.
I am sure you are aware of this fact,
but the Cabinet Intelligence Agency is an organisation that,
under the supervision of the Chief Cabinet Secretary,
mainly serves to collect and analyse
both domestic and foreign intelligence,
and to sometimes manipulate public opinion.
We would prefer to have you consider this request to be a
direct order from the Chief Cabinet Secretary himself.
After all, we can hardly expect the Prime Minister's
crisis-management abilities to lead to rapid decision-making.
What the hell is that?
What is that thing's refuelling capacity?
If its specs haven't changed,
it can supply six years' worth of fuel for a car.
Even though the Digger Wasp is a fuel hog, the tanker
should have enough fuel to keep it airborne for ten hours.
Well, it seems as if it's
distributing fuel to all the units,
so if you do a simple calculation, each unit
should be able to fly for at least another hour.
Assuming that the Digger Wasp has an
average cruise duration of 2.5 hours,
one would assume that they have less than
an hour's worth of flight time remaining.
What's the possibility that that flying
jerry can over there will go down first?
Zero.
The Flower Beetle will go down last.
After all, it's becoming lighter and lighter.
That means its cruise duration will increase.
Hey, Batou-San. They're AIs, just like us, right?
Well, yeah, although they're support-type AIs designed with
the assumption that there'll be a human pilot on board.
Still, not only are they presently without pilots,
they're also staying airborne
of their own free will, right?
They really must've disliked
their labour conditions.
Are the military's labour conditions that harsh?
Jeez, gloomy AIs snap so easily!
We still have to fight them if we get orders?
That's right.
Anti-tank helicopters would be
our natural enemies, right...?
Batou-San, Batou-San!
What?
Can we go home? We have upset stomachs.
Stomachs? Where?
Looks like the GSDF went too close.
They tried to dive into the
support AIs and failed, probably.
The GSDF pilot's salary must be pretty low, huh?
Revenge
Samurai
Ueda SDF Store
Chief.
What's going on? Why did you
bother to come all the way here?
Were you unable to free yourself
from the Prime Minister's "leash"?
Major, let me explain.
He is an agent with the Cabinet
Intelligence Agency, and...
A representative aide of the Investigative Council
for Possible Changes to Wartime Strategy, Gouda.
I will state the conclusions first.
Section 9 will soon be granted complete
freedom to resolve this situation.
However, I'd like for you to conduct the
operation entirely according to his plan.
Old man, are you insane?!
We didn't stay in Section 9 just
to become the government's dogs.
According to our calculations,
the first unit will crash into the
residential refugee sector in 48 minutes.
The damage will become
irreparable once that occurs.
This is obviously an act of terrorism.
What will you do?
Fine.
Let's hear your plan.
Nice and obedient; good.
Major, assuming we take
everything he said at face value,
why would you agree to his plan?
Even supposing that the pilot's sudden death and
the AI's rampage weren't an act of terrorism,
if one of the helicopters crashes,
this area will sustain damage.
There is no guarantee that the refugee situation
won't become a powder keg if that happens.
Besides, without his information,
we didn't have a hand to play, anyway.
What I meant to ask was what our
stance was in all of this, and...
Never mind.
Saitou, are you ready?
I'm ready.
All right.
So, they indiscriminately
attack anything that moves...
Let's start.
All right, let's go!
They're gonna come after us!
Don't go back down to ground level.
If we do, we won't be able to
evade Air-to-Surface Missiles if they lock on to us!
The odds are totally against us.
Not only is the ratio two-to-one,
but we're inferior in firepower to begin with.
Good, it's as he said.
Batou, the target unit is tailing me.
I'm counting on you.
Target confirmed.
Major, when you pass in front of me,
make the target tilt up.
I'd like to shoot through the canopy's side
in order to shoot the pilot
without destroying the AI.
Roger that.
Tachikoma!
It accepted the control tower's
code disengagement command.
I'm glad our predictions were accurate.
We predicted that once the cyberbrain signals of the
pilot, who had suffered cardiac arrest, were cut,
the support AI would accept the control
tower's code disengagement command.
In addition, I exercised good judgement
in requesting your aid in this matter.
Thanks to you, we were able to avoid having the SDF
troops bear the stain of having killed one of their own.
Then what?
You mean you don't care if
Saitou has to bear that stain?
Batou, I'm used to it.
Good job.
The return of all eleven units has been confirmed.
Have you heard Togusa's report?
No.
Cardiac medication was found in that pilot's home.
It appears he was hiding his
ailment from his superiors.
Then, are you suggesting that this incident
wasn't an act of terrorism, as Gouda insisted,
but instead was just an accident?
Then, are you suggesting that this incident
wasn't an act of terrorism, as Gouda insisted,
but instead was just an accident?
I don't know.
Until we conduct a structural analysis of the
medication we found and the deceased pilot's blood,
there's no way to confirm either way.
The Cabinet Intelligence Agency's aide appeared at just
the right moment, and it seemed as if he knew everything.
In addition, the GSDF helicopters flew directly above the
refugees in such a way as to unnecessarily provoke them,
as if that was their intention.
What is the significance of all of this?
It could be that crime on a massive scale
is in the works, somewhere unknown to us.
Finding out a galaxy
of planets and stars within me.
Listening to each of them
and singing the same silent melody.
I've never seen such beauty
in possibility...
No smack of doubt or fear.
(Wake up)
I hear a voice.
(And show the light)
hear a voice calling out to me.
(Wake up)
I see inside
(Our time is now)
see the light now ever holding me.
All the truth,
(All the truth)
All I need,
to make all this reality.
(it's inside)
The beauty within the shell.
(deep within the shell)
(within the shell)
(Wake up)
I hear a voice
(And show the light)
hear a voice calling out to me.
(Wake up)
(the time is now)
I see inside,
see the light now ever holding me.
(the time is now)
All the truth,
(All the truth)
to make all this reality,
it's inside
right here within the shell.